all right cool we're rolling dude Joel I
uh I have a little surprise for you at
the beginning of this episode that I
wasn't going to tell you about
um I'm super excited because I just went
on to our Spotify and there are 56
five-star reviews on on Spotify are you
serious yeah man I was super surprised
when I went in there you guys really
came through for us on those Spotify
reviews so thank you so much for that
and on top of that we have 10 five star
reviews on uh Apple podcasts
um and and five of them are like or four
of them are actual like text reviews so
I want to just give a shout out right
now to deaf param max power 99 1911
Rocky and Joseph Fuego 555 for dropping
some awesome reviews for us on Apple
podcasts we really appreciate that and
that really keeps us hyped to keep
producing content dude that's so awesome
yeah thanks a lot to everybody who's
been taking the time to listen we've
been getting a ton of good feedback on
Twitter everybody says that they're
really enjoying listening to the content
so we're just glad to be you know
pushing this out and hope you keep
enjoying it it's so exciting right man I
people have been tweeting and stuff like
that and every time I just get like
hyped to go do some research for the
next episode and stuff so yeah
definitely appreciate that but um yeah
okay so I guess let's just Dive Right In
today
um actually you know what before we so
we're going to talk today about the
portswiger top 10
um web hacking techniques of 2022 which
was pretty much the big biggest piece of
content that was released over the past
couple weeks sort of outlining what the
top web hacking techniques of 2022 were
and kind of do a little bit of a I don't
know if we can do a deep dive because
it's there's 10 of them and we've only
got an hour here but we're just gonna
try to skate over each one of those give
some comments on them talk about the
various
um
techniques but before that the drama
Joel the drama because we shouted out
truffle sack on our podcast a couple
weeks ago and [__] hit the fan so tell
me a little bit about that yeah so you
you may have seen there was some drama
on Twitter and whatnot but basically I
believe that the the tldr is that
truffle security with the new
exercise Hunter basically
um
they were logging statistics about you
know callbacks and all that kind of
stuff security people don't like that
[__] man they really don't and yeah they
tweeted out like a summary that was
essentially here's all the callbacks
that we've had you know successful
exploits all that kind of stuff and
people were pretty pissed because they
were like hang on a second you're
looking at our stats you're looking at
our callbacks you could just be taking
our bugs you could just be saying yes
zero days that are being exploited so
yeah I've seen some people
um mention that you should self-host
your own instance of xss Hunter which is
definitely a viable option if you have a
server or you want to just spin up a
little instance
and I've even seen some programs go as
far as to say that they won't accept
reports that are using an externally
hosted xss Hunter yeah I saw that too it
was right right surrounding this drama
too I think right like one of the
biggest programs
out there kind of send out a message on
hacker one and said like hey if you use
a non-self hosted xss Hunter instance
then no Bounty for you
yeah yeah and that's like I I think it's
pretty rare when I see a program react
to that quickly and that um
aggressively I guess
um which is pretty pretty surprising but
I think it's a generally a good move I
think that truffle security has also
sort of stepped back and said you know
this wasn't really intentional we were
just trying to celebrate the use of the
product we're not trying to steal your
bugs or anything but I think the point
remains that you know this is something
you should probably just think about and
keep an eye on if you're using
externally hosted tools just remember
that
those people can have logs of anything
you're putting in there right so if
you're putting in a zero day or some bug
that hasn't been reported or released
you never know who's going to see that
you never know with access to those logs
so just
be cautious think before you paste all
that kind of stuff yeah man I don't know
I I maybe it's a hot take and I I am
notoriously not privacy conscious you
know like I've got Google homes all over
my house and you know all sorts of stuff
like that but don't don't use that
against me guys maybe I shouldn't
publicly admit that on the podcast but
um I don't know man I I I don't think
it's that big of a deal I mean clearly
it was just statistic it's not like
they're in here like saying hey you know
run reader congrats on your blindxes
that would be creepy that would be
creepy but in this case it's just it's
just statistics and um
you know obviously it's not a great idea
anyway because
um vulnerabilities they're you know they
definitely should be try to kept private
between the Poke Bounty Hunter and the
the you know company you're reporting it
to and so there's definitely some some I
I definitely understand from the program
side them saying something like hey we
don't want to see this and on a program
but I I think the backlash on Twitter
was a little bit
um a little bit over overdone especially
considering the fact that truffle
security is providing a free service to
us and actually went in and enhanced the
product and then was just kind of
celebrating their their dub on like oh
you know we got cool get issues Cloud
credentials and cores popping up so I
don't know maybe that's a hot take yeah
no I I think I'm with you on that it's
like
it's kind of tricky because on one hand
we want to be like very like security
positive and on the other hand like they
have a product they need to like promote
it right I don't think that Trump
security is doing what people are sort
of like alluding to which is that
they're going into the logs they're
looking at the things your callbacks and
then they're taking your bugs and like
doing who knows what with them I would
be very surprised right if you think
about it from like a business
perspective
it's not great Optics if that's what
you're doing yeah if that were to get
out in any way which since people are
already kind of like
saying that that could be a thing it
would be a pretty dumb idea and they're
a security company right like that I
feel like they have
some ethics already yeah like they they
kind of know
um and in their statement they sort of
addressed that so I think it is a little
bit of an aggressive move from the
community
um just being like you know screwed
trouble security host your own and all
that kind of stuff but
um you know security people are going to
be security people they are they are and
different paranoid yeah and you know the
Privacy piece I don't know I I have
definitely been called out a couple
times about not being conscious about
that but I also feel like that almost it
almost feels to me like delusions of
grandeur right like if I were like if I
were like you know I don't know like
head of the CIA or something like that
and people had a reason to like want to
get in my Google home and just hear like
the stupid conversations I have with my
wife or like you know weird [__] like
that then then I would be a little bit
more security conscious but like at the
end of the day I'm a podcast host I'm a
I'm a solo entrepreneur Buck Bounty
Hunter like
you know who's really going to go
through all the trouble to and use a
Google home exploit to you know pop me
so I don't know I don't know that's just
how I said that like your threat model
should be your threat model yeah like
yeah it doesn't have to be like a
universal threat model like you you sort
of should just look at your life look at
your context and decide what how secure
need to be yeah so like if you're
worried that somebody's gonna be
dropping a zero day on you is that a
valid concern yeah maybe like maybe some
Russian State like actor is gonna drop a
zero day on yeah I don't know man I have
heard some pretty some pretty like crazy
[__] though about like
foreign States and vulnerability
researchers so you know I'll definitely
you know my threat model definitely
includes being careful around specific
foreign countries but
um yeah so all right making me go back
and forth on this maybe maybe I I know I
know well we'll we'll talk about it off
off the air but yeah there's definitely
some weird stuff that's happened
um but yeah okay okay so
truffle truffle security that's our take
um take it or leave it your threat
models your own risk if you're really
concerned host it yourself that's pretty
much it or or
and you didn't get this advice here use
it and then when you get the call back
go host your own and then do it again
and get the call back again and report
that
you know didn't hear it here
you know I don't know who that was that
just took over the mic but
um uh all right no no okay so the next
thing that I wanted to talk about real
quick before we hop into the um
portsmaker top 10 was uh well two things
real quick two just little news blurbs
um phuff released phuff 2.0 and it's got
some real nice new features surrounding
um being able to track back which
requests
um caused a certain functionality
um and then also being able to extract
data out of your fuff which would you
know your faf searches or your Brute
Forces which I think is a huge feature I
use that in Intruder all the time you
know they'll like match and extract sort
of feature in Intruder so definitely
love to see that as always
knocks it out of the park
I don't know I'm sorry bro but knocks
you knock it out of the park with fuff
so thank you for that awesome Community
contribution and just wanted to shout it
out and then also Kai released a super
nice HTML preview feature which I use
all the time in burp sweep and I was was
stinging a little bit it took a little
getting used to to not have that in
kaido and now I can just have it in
kaido so another great reason to check
kaido out yeah yeah that's awesome and
when we were talking about um ffuf
um I was I was just thinking about a
conversation I had with Jay Haddix
not long ago about the like the scanner
brute force or search or whatever that
that he uses yeah and he uses one called
fairox Buster which I had never heard of
yeah I think I did hear him mention this
yeah it's a it's a really cool tool it's
written in Rust super fast
um and he actually prefers it over ffuf
I believe
um wow mainly just because it does like
it has some nice features like you can
interrupt it you can modify the search
as it's going in real time
with those uh with those results that
it's already found
um and it's written in Rust I think ffuf
is go right yeah that's right yeah yeah
so probably a little bit faster
um but uh it's really it's really cool
other other nice Tools in this space I
use both kind of depending on use case
but
um I've definitely been leaning a little
bit towards fairox Buster just for the
different use cases and to try out that
new tool so definitely check them both
out but the new version of ffuf V2 is
like packed full of awesome features
like you were talking about so if you
haven't updated your ffuf in a while
update it and give it a run and check it
out the content Discovery Wars continue
I feel like every couple years I'm I'm
switching you know from from product to
product just chasing the the extra you
know little bit of efficiency or the
nice new features so always always
appreciate the skin with python oh my
gosh dude I I still have code running on
my server that scans with pie because
you know sometimes you just need to be
you just need slow and steady you know
all right cool well let's with that
let's um let's go ahead and hop into the
portswiger top 10 web hacking techniques
drum roll
I don't know if you can hear that but
I'm drum rolling dude I get so excited
when I see this every year because these
techniques are such fire and I it
actually took quite a few hours
um to read through all of these in prep
for this podcast
um because they're so good and so in
depth and a lot of them are really
really complex so I've still got a
couple in here that I don't fully
understand
um so hopefully we can kind of talk that
through or maybe someone in the one of
our listeners can pop in and explain it
to me but yeah 100
um a lot of these I was surprised I
hadn't even heard about them and I was
reading through them and they're they're
all like fantastic write-ups it kind of
varies across the space the quality of
write-ups that you can see but these are
all very top tier well-written well
documented well explained they had
diagrams and pictures and yeah
definitely very well written write-ups
so I would encourage anybody who's
curious about more of these we'll link
it in the description below but we'll
put the top 10 uh list from Port swiger
we'll put the article there and you can
look through them all and there's also
they included the list of nominees
um that's always a good read even more
there's like an infinite list of like
Wizards that you can read through there
but these
I think I honestly prefer it to the OAS
top 10 a wasp is just a little too
generic for me and I really appreciate
the level of specificity that each of
these goes into where it's more like a
specific bug and it talks about sort of
the methodology and stuff behind it yeah
no that makes sense I I you know the
last top 10 I think definitely has its
its spot but this is sort of in a
different category for me personally
because yeah these are actual you know
specific techniques and Hands-On
um you know vulnerabilities which has a
different ring to it and also I just I
love the fact that this uh I just wanted
to shout out file descriptor on here
he's on the expert panel of researchers
that kind of helps put together this I
haven't seen much from him in the past
couple of years
um since before before kovid but I love
that guy and he does a great job with
um and the rest of this panel is
obviously amazing too
um so thank you for the excellent work
people over at portswiger and people on
the panel for this top 10 web hacking
techniques that can always be almost
like 100 certain that there's some
really crazy cool research going on
behind the scenes when filing oh yeah
he's being quiet oh I know yeah yeah I
can't wait to see what he comes up with
man I still he's still like my go-to
like if I have some weird to your cat is
on top of your printer you want to break
my printer thing
um yeah man he's still my go-to whenever
I have like some crazy like hey is this
possible in any you know edge browser
versions or like weird stuff like that
he's he's the one so all right cool
let's check out number 10
um on the list this one goes to none
other than Mr Curry Sam himself Mr
Zazzle as he's known in the in the live
hacking circuit
um this is a uh Universal xss on netlify
and actually dude I'm a little salty
about this one I told this to Sam too
because he told me about this when he
was before he released it and I was like
dude I freaking knew there was bugs in
that and those endpoints like I just
didn't that's just one of these ones
that I like had it on my list of sketchy
stuff and then I actually just never
went down the hole and then you know
some crazy bugs pop up later so Props to
say before that feeling when you're like
it's like it's tingling you're like
hacker like spidey sense and you're like
I should put this on my list maybe I'll
check it out later
six months later you're dealing with too
many other things and then boom out of
nowhere blog posts and you're like
I knew it yeah yeah
so
um all right I'll take let's let's do it
this way I'll talk about there's three
bugs in this one
um I'll talk about one you talk about
two and then we'll join talk about three
or whatever so the first bug on this on
this little list here is an open
redirect and it's pretty uh fairly
straightforward but one of the things I
do want to highlight here is that um
it utilizes uh something that I think
people should be aware of in in these
sort of situations is the way that
browsers redirect
um when you give backslashes and and uh
like for example you don't have to have
https in the beginning of your location
header uh to get an open redirect you
can do it with Slash you can do it with
some combination of slashes and
backslashes so um when you're looking
trying to break a regex for open
redirection or something of the like
then definitely
um you know kind of play around with all
these different values and and sometimes
you can even get chains where you know
you give it one thing and then it
redirects to
um something else and then when it
normalizes the thing that you told it to
redirect to that causes a redirect
um so I brilliant work here by Sam as
well and I think Sam was also one of the
people that kind of helped Foster this
behavior in me as well just kind of
seeing Sam's bug at life hacking event
and just from hacking together so yeah
yeah really really good stuff here and I
love how he also mentions that a lot of
these sites are also using oauth and you
know later in the top 10 list we'll talk
about oauth and how you can use open
redirects to try to do stuff with oauth
so definitely not shying away from
dropping as an open redirect the other
day because it can definitely be used in
in chains for much more impact yeah I
feel open redirects are one of those
things that
like in the beginning like it's one of
the first things that you think is like
oh this is a cool bug but the more you
push into it the more you're like this
isn't like quite
this isn't quite severe enough to be
like something to just report on itself
but then just like one step further is
you just get a little more experience
you realize like it's a perfect like
chain mechanism and if you find one just
like write it down keep track of it
give it to like work with somebody else
on it because almost certainly there's a
really good use case where we can
escalate that impact yeah yeah I you
rarely have to report them on uh you
know alone you can almost always
escalate them and use them in some other
parts of chains yeah so the second thing
that um that Sam and I don't know if Sam
was working alone on this or if they
were working with other people but the
second thing that they found was uh both
in ssrf and an xss
um so essentially there was this path
that you could get within the netlify
ipx library
um and you do slash I think underscore
ipx and then W underscore 200 I think
that's from basically like a thumbnail
type you give it a resolution or
whatever and then you would in the path
you would URL encode an hdb URL and it
would just fetch it and it would check
for it to be an SVG and then it would
just render it so if your SVG had an
exercise payload in it because SVG is
Vector based so you can put elements in
it and you can Run Access through it so
they would ssrf out to your server
assuming I think there was actually a
host check somewhere yeah it says in
here that there's
um some white list and he was a little
bit frustrated that it wasn't a totally
Universal exploit which
dude as a piece of software you don't
want to go up against a frustrated Sam
Curry man so yeah but this is one of
those use cases that we were talking
about right open reacts this is a
perfect example if there's some sort of
host uh if there's a host whitelist
allow list and you need to get around
that find an open redirect within that
host and then use it to get to your own
knows yeah no absolutely and so for the
third one where he does fully you know
get arbitrary Universal xss on any of
these instances and of these netplify uh
instances is when he gets into the you
know white box source code review which
is really I think I think this is a
technique that I've been working on with
my mentees a little bit more lately and
um they've been really eating up is this
getting into the code really starting to
you know read through Trace Trace data
inputs and it would have been very hard
to find this otherwise I think but what
he does here is he goes through and he
finds in the in the source code for
netlify PX he finds the exported
protocol header is being parsed and
integrated into
um
these requests and you know it it it's
it's easy to think okay well that's just
would just be for protocols but after
reading the code he actually finds that
you can just stick a whole URL in there
as the protocol and uh and then just
truncate the rest of the request using a
question mark at the end or I'm sure you
could use a hashtag as well making it a
part of the URL fragment and then the
end that's the thing that that gives him
the full ssrf and I want to point out
here one of the things that Sam does
really well which is Sam understands the
threat model here right um you know he
normally if he's got an ssrf zero day
he'd be talking about the ssrf not the
xss but these are static websites
um and so at the end of the day there's
not a lot of impact to the ssrf and
there is literally the most impact you
can possibly have on these static
websites is xss and so he does he does a
really good job here of highlighting
that actually this results in cross-site
scripting which is the primary impact in
these sort of scenarios so shout out to
Sam for for that and for not getting
distracted by the cool shiny bug type
name of ssrf and and actually following
the threat model for the websites yeah
and I think another great thing to call
out here is that this is next Jazz right
so next.js is used very very frequently
within web 3 websites
um where you're dealing with nfts
minting and wallets and approvals and
there's a lot of
there's a lot of risk at hand and so
being able to have arbitrary like xss on
any of those websites is huge because
most of the time these websites are
designed very very specifically to only
let you mint a certain thing or sign a
certain message or something like that
with your wallet
and if you can make the user do
something else completely unexpected you
could literally empty their wallet you
could steal all of their money so oh my
gosh so impact a huge amount of risk and
the fact that it's Universal and it's
such a widely used Library it's just an
awesome finding yeah way to go Sam at
all on that one
um jumping to number nine on the list
we've got uh let's see who is this by it
says Medi in the uh
list but I'm not actually familiar with
this hacker so I'm gonna have to check
them out but I am familiar with and
absolutely love client-side patch
reversals and it's just such a little
scrappy bug that you're like really are
you trying to make something out of a
client-side patch reversal but dude it
really has some some crazy impact
sometime
um and I always I always pay attention
to these because anytime you're taking
user input and you're integrating it
into requests it you know there's
there's potential there's risk there and
I think even as we see more and more of
same-site strict adoption happening and
I talked about this in other podcasts
but I'll say it again as we see same
site strict or even same site lacks but
it's particularly same-site strict
getting adopted by more and more
websites in the future this is going to
be the new c-surf is trying to figure
out how to make these requests trying to
abuse the requests that websites are
making on their own from the same origin
and then using that for your for your
benefit and I think think this this
hacker here does a really good job of
doing this in this in this write-up yeah
100 and we've talked about this in
previous episodes because I think
actually one of the bugs that we talked
about was a client side uh yeah it had
some pieces of it yeah yeah and so very
similar concept
um obviously it's
it's Case by case but this is another
one of those great examples where
chaining bugs together open Reader X and
um sort of thinking about the context of
the application and building that impact
scenario around the application just
like a great use case so essentially the
bug is that there was a parameter that
you could provide in the URL
and it would cause the client to load a
CSS with that parameter in the URL
and so they were able to chain this with
an open redirect that they had found and
a path traversal so the dot dot slash
dot slash and then hit their open
redirect path and open redirect it to
an attacker-controlled resource that is
a CSS file and then you use CSS
exfiltration which is something that
we've also freaking loved that man uh
yeah they're at some point we should
maybe give a full oh yeah discussion
I've got such a I'm sorry to steal it
but I've just got such a crazy bug such
a crazy CSS injection bug that I've got
to talk about on this stream
um so that's coming I'm going to tease
you all right now it's so good
um but yeah okay we'll talk about that
later continue sorry yeah no and I mean
I wanted you to talk about because we
had mentioned it like this this is the
Singapore bug right uh no this is
actually so that so this is actually my
bug um and I know the Singapore bug uh
was well actually I won't say whose [__]
it was but
um really awesome hacker but dude
actually I'm not sure you've even seen
this one because you weren't in uh
actually I can't say what it is either
because that also gives it away but I
don't know that you saw this one because
you weren't in person at this event I
think you were you were um
you were remote so I'm not sure you you
tuned into the show and tell but um it's
it's probably the bug that I am most
proud of like as far as like I just put
a crap ton of time in here and it just
uses all these different like Scrappy
Edge techniques and in the end it comes
together so beautifully
um so anyway okay I'll talk about it a
different time
to hear about that at the end okay so
yeah like like Joel said
um taking a parameter so you know you
redirect the victim to a specific URL
with an attacker controlled parameter
um and that that parameter gets injected
into a CSS file which is dynamically
loaded based off of that input you use
the input to do a path traversal
hidden open redirect that you found and
that redirects to the attacker
controlled CSS file and when the
attacker CSS code is loaded on the
website you can use that to exfiltrate
things like csrf tokens or user data and
then if you do you know csrf tokens
you've just got full access to c-serv so
a lot of times you can get account
takeover or or something like that so
really really creative flow here love it
Medi uh congratulations on the on the
winning of uh being put into the list I
don't even know is it called it's not
called a nomination what is the
final round candidates is the the yeah
congrats for being in the top 10. yeah
cool
um yeah so number what is this number
not eight number eight yeah so number
eight man this was a an insane bug I was
I was reading through this and I was
like how is this oh my gosh that was
responsible that this is I know freaking
I cannot believe that some and I love
how also just before you explain this
one because I'll you take this one Joel
but I just want to say like I love how
in here
uh in this article they talk about how
like what things should have saved them
like what kind of like weird little like
weird math things or like weird checks
that actually should have made it like
you know we see that all the time in
bugs like you have this attack vector
and then like the developer just gets
lucky and like some weird thing doesn't
work out and it breaks the whole exploit
and he he notes uh the author here notes
a couple of them
um and they just you know what what what
things could have happened but actually
didn't to save them and it just seems
like a perfect storm for this
vulnerability God we've talked about
this so often but read the docs okay
yeah man read the docs read how it's
supposed to work and then look at how
it's actually for sure right because
this is something that happens over and
over again and we're gonna see this also
in some of the other bugs that we talk
about
um in this list but reading the docs is
so huge actually the next one we talked
about is gonna also be a very big read
the docs moment right so essentially
this bug was
um a lack of ecdsa signature
verification in like Java 15 16 17 and
18. oh my gosh so
um yeah so essentially what happened is
uh the Java implementation of ecdsa got
Rewritten from C plus into native Java
and when that happened uh the migration
was missing a lot of these safety checks
that should have been in the ecdsa
algorithm for hashing
um and so essentially what happened is
if you gave it a signature that's all
zeros
tldr is that the math is zero times
anything is zero right and so if you
multiply a blank signature that's all
zeros by anything it's always going to
come back valid and so
I mean it sounds like it's successful it
hurts me it hurts me man it really does
it's it's so crazy and uh this blog does
a great job of sort of walking you
through without getting like super super
technical because yeah I think if you
any time you sort of delve into like the
crypto side like the elliptic curves the
cryptography side to be clear yes the
cryptography not not the cryptocurrency
the cryptographies uh that crypto yeah
um it can I mean even for me it goes way
over my head a lot of the time yeah yeah
but this was to a level that even I
could understand yeah essentially what
happens is like I said if you give it a
fully blank signature if you look at the
math behind the scenes zero times
anything is zero what if my cat is
trying dude what is the cat doing man
all right dude I think this might be the
one I think this is going to be the one
that we're gonna post video so if you
want to see what is this Joel's cat is
eating out of here I don't know what is
he even doing but this is the one okay
no but yeah man I totally agree I think
you know he really talks about the
basics of you know R and S and and I'm
to be clear as well I I I'm not big on
the on the math side of things people
hear oh you're a hacker oh you computer
science you know must be a math boy I'm
not a math boy
um so but yeah no this stuff is simple
enough and really
um uh well explained um the perfect the
perfect example of what you want to see
in a write-up I think
um so shout out to the norm of bad
things and one of the awesome things
Neil that I that I bookmarked that was
mentioned and I had never heard of this
but there's a thing called project uh I
think it's weish proof oh yeah I saw
that yeah it's how it's printed I'm not
really sure um
w-y-c-h-e-p-r-o-o-f I have no idea it's
by um the Google security team and
essentially what it's designed to do is
it runs crypto libraries through
like a standard test suite and it'll
feed like known crypto issues including
this bug that was talked about with a
blank signature being validated
incorrectly and it lets you sort of
Sanity check to make sure that
everything is working right and uh Neil
said that he ran it he you know updated
weishproof to work with the Java
versions that he was testing against and
sure enough he found it immediately wow
so I think that's a really great thing
if you're working at a company
or maybe you're auditing something
crypto specific maybe just run it
through that wise proof tool and see if
it finds anything because that's
certainly a lot easier than doing all
the auditing yourself and trying to find
the nuances within the code if it'll
just be like hey there's there's an
issue here and here's what it is
wow yeah dude that's that's awesome I I
I'd also just want to say about on the
topic of weish proof I I clicked on the
the GitHub repo and at the top of the
GitHub repo it says like uh project
twice proof is named after Mount
weishproof the smallest mountain in the
world and then you go here and it's like
it's it's got a on Wikipedia it's got a
picture of just like a field it's like
this is a mountain
yeah
wait okay I'm looking at this is yeah I
don't even know man I don't I have no
idea so yeah shout out to Google for
yeah crazy 138 feet tall or 42 meters
that's so small dude
I feel like I'm about to go on a rabbit
hole about what makes him not an amount
don't don't do it Joel don't do it man
don't do it don't get nerd sniped by
Google
um yeah no I I really also like the one
thing that I did want to shout out was
the multiplicative inverse um
explanation
um really clean really simple
um and it shows that he really did his
due diligence and died diving into the
code and really understanding all the
pieces so
um shout out to Neil Madden and congrats
for making into the top ten yeah that
really makes me think about some other
like migrations that are like that
because I mean it's just Java he
mentioned that this is used in JWT and a
lot of other like very core like
functions yeah and it makes me wonder
what other migrations have happened in
other languages from either like C plus
pops C plus plus bindings to native
language bindings or other instances of
that where they may have forgotten some
checks and there might be some other
really really critical CVS in there yeah
for sure and I would like to just to
take away for the people
um that are listening uh if you want to
or maybe I'll do this after we'll see
but I would love to just go ahead and
generate this zero signature I don't I
mean I don't know if it's actually like
do you need
you know 64 bytes of zero or something
like that for like a JWT you know how
like there's some weird stuff in
um what's the bird plug-in I want to say
it's like Joseph or something like that
where you throw a JWT in there and then
it like Signs it with like
um you know none or something like that
and it's just an empty string and it
modifies the the first part of the JWT
and stuff like that I do that every time
I see a JWT because one time I found one
and it was like oh my gosh this is nuts
um and so I I would also it would be
really cool to just have like be able to
like paste a signature in there
um and and check and see if that that
works and see if they're using a
vulnerable version of java so it'd be
great to like tweet out that like 64
byte whatever it is and and do it that
way yeah this is reminding me of
um I've seen this in a couple ctfs and
puzzles but essentially it'll be using
the default like or like the example
code as in your in your like production
so if you're uh yeah like just the like
the readme page and like how to encrypt
with
insert crypto library and then you copy
paste that code typically there'll be
like a default key or default ID or
something in there and if it ever gets
left then
super easy win or same thing with if
they're using an empty key or null key
and you can replicate that and you can
resign your own
yeah I know for jwts you can you can
pretty easily check this by just going
to like jwt.io and you can just paste
your JWT in there and you can resign it
and it'll tell you whether or not it's
valid for a given signing key and so you
can test with like an empty key or a
known key
um or an example key and you can see
whether or not they may have signed it
using that okay yeah I I was trying to
remember the person who who wrote this
it was Ian Carroll there's actually a
couple years ago he released a tool
called Cookie Monster which helps check
for like uh default keys and stuff like
that in for vulnerable session cookies
in particular on
um several different Frameworks Express
rack flask Django lar laravel man this
is so you know what's weird about doing
a podcast Joel like you start reading
all of the you know you've read only
ever read it the words you've only ever
read and you know you think that would
be gone by the time you're like you know
25 or something words you've only read
in books like Oh I'm a wordy kid that
reads books or whatever but no when
you're in the tech world there's so many
different names and stuff that you've
only ever read and never said out loud
it's a gotcha man it really is but yeah
I'll link this in the I'll link this in
the description for
um of the of the Pod and you guys can
check out Cookie Monster by Ian Carroll
yeah yeah that's a great example I know
that there was another uh I think this
might be what I'm thinking of but
essentially yeah the flat like the
default flask encryption keys and stuff
yeah
um and you see that in ctfs all the time
yeah where it's like oh like how would
we ever get the secret value and then
you like you go and you look up and sure
enough there's you know it's one two
three four one two three four one two
three four or something like that yeah
all right cool let's keep rolling
because we're only a couple down the
list
um yeah we might have to split this into
a double episode this week or something
but
um all right number seven uh dude we
were both really excited about this one
pre-episode um what an amazing concept
this one is
um so essentially uh the tldr on this
one is there's these things called hop
by hop headers and I have no idea that's
Exclusive by the way I know man yeah I
had read the research when it originally
came out and then I was like oh that's
so cool I should you know it went into
that list of like you know research that
I should flesh out that I never flesh
out
um and never came back out of there but
luckily
Jacob Poe
Ted EOS we're getting back into I know
man I'm so sorry I feel so bad uh yeah
you know I should be able to pronounce
this too because I used to speak Italian
but now my Italian's gone
um
but uh yeah
it's it's a great it's a great write-up
and there's these things called hop by
hop headers and essentially what they
allow you to do is remove specific
headers at specific points in the
processing of an HTTP request so if
you've got a reverse proxy and then
another reverse proxy and then the
actual server
you can specify like okay I need this
header removed at the first you know
proxy or if you just got a reverse proxy
on a server as well
um so that's a really cool concept and
could potentially allow for I would also
really like to see um people trying to
do the same thing that um uh uh that
James Kettle does with uh request
smuggling in here with this header so
like for example if you go through the
first proxy and then uh you know it does
not process process the connection
header with an extra space after the end
uh and and then the colon but the second
one does then you can remove headers
that were added by the first proxy and
you know it would be crazy
um but yeah so happy that they actually
took this research that was done years
before actually I want to say right
um was it three years before yeah I
believe it was three years uh three
years before yeah dude that's crazy let
me find it yeah Nathan Nathan Davidson
um yeah dude I went back and read this
one yesterday definitely a good read
Nathan Davidson does a write-up on like
okay this is weird we should start
looking at this and he's totally right
and then finally you know these guys are
able to pull it off a couple years later
um yeah it's enough and like we talked
about in the previous in the previous
bug this is a perfect example just read
the document read the documentation and
take a look at what's actually happening
I had no idea that this was a thing and
if you read the RFC I mean this is from
1997. okay yeah it's been 25 years old
it's you know but it's been around for
quite some time and it literally says
explicitly in here that there are like
two categories of HTTP headers
end-to-end headers which are
carried throughout the entire request
and hop by hop headers which are meant
for transport level connections and
they're not stored or used uh after
they're forwarded by a proxy or a cache
and they say here are the hop by hop
headers and they list specifically
connection keep alive public proxy
authenticate transfer encoding upgrade
all other headers defined as buy HTTP
1.1 are end-to-end headers hop by hop
headers introduced in future versions of
HTTP must be listed in a connection
header okay like it's like ver extremely
verbose it explains exactly how this
should happen and be like huh cool and
just keep moving but uh jacoba did an
amazing you know they sort of like
turned it around they were like hang on
a second if we send two requests
concatenated together like in request
smuggling and there's headers that we
need to remove here
I could just Define it as a hop by hop
header and put it in the connection
header in my first request and it'll get
removed and sure enough exactly by the
spec it gets removed it's so crazy so
cool yeah yeah no I totally agree
reading reading the docs big big dub um
and so just a just a tldr
um what happened here so they would send
the request and this request would have
a uh content linked header of 53 in a
Content body that was actually another
HTTP request and then it would specify
the connection header as the um and the
content linked header inside of the
connection header as a hop by hop sort
of header here then when the first proxy
was was processing it it would split the
it would pull off the the content length
header then it would split the requests
into two different requests and then
what would end up happening is the
response to that request would get sent
back to the user the the request that
was inside of the request body that was
originally a part of the request body
gets parsecessed and processed and
parsed as its own request and gets sent
back to the user
or actually the proper thing to say
would it gets gets put back into the
response queue
um on the on the Akamai proxy and then
you can trigger that by reaching out
with another request
so really awesome job here essentially
what they what it allowed you know this
this team to do was just send that that
request and return back just arbitrary
content which is devastating and this
affected I want to say the whole Akamai
CDN yeah I think it was on every Edge
node which is which is kind of that's
not like absurd
um one of the awesome things that jacoba
did was they put this uh this diagram in
their blog that does a really great job
of visualizing sort of the flow of how
this works for your use and your request
and you include the hop by hop header in
your connection header in the first
request it hits the first proxy it gets
split into two requests handled by the
second proxy two different responses
then get sent back to the first proxy
one goes into the queue one goes back to
the requester and then essentially it's
just standard HTTP request modeling yeah
yeah beautiful beautiful graph really
good job jacobo and team
um yeah yeah and the the GIF that they
put in there with the POC was just like
I I was I was sitting at my desk and I
was just looking at that and I was like
are you serious and I like had to zoom
in and I was like no way yeah it's just
like a curl request and then they hit at
some other arbitrary path and it just
returns you know robots.txt on like some
hacker one
underscore.js it's like you know it's
it's an amazing POC it's
awesome yeah it is yeah about halfway
down on the page there just stunning you
can just upload any content you want to
you know paypal.com was the one they're
using here really really awesome bug all
right dude it looks like we might only
get through
maybe the top six today we might have to
do another one later this week or cover
it again next week but let's talk about
number six and then we'll we'll sort of
wrap it up cool yeah so um essentially
this this was actually researched
directly from James Kettle who works at
portswiger and this was uh talking about
uh injecting a separate HTTP request uh
and very similar to the previous bug but
with like response cueing and all that
kind of stuff
the attack Factor was very interesting
when I was reading through this it took
me a second to actually understand how
it was going through but essentially the
whole payload goes right in your request
path so if you think about how an HTTP
request actually works
um like when you request you know
example.com Fubar right
it's going to go make an HTTP request
that's get space slash Fubar space HTTP
1.1 Etc and
the whole payload you would URL encode
you know new lines slash r n or percent
zero to e percent zero a and then you
put host headers and all that kind of
stuff and it would get
decoded URL decoded and basically the
full raw request would then use two full
requests in there so James explained
that somebody had reached out to him and
was like Hey I have this weird bug I
don't really know how to exploit this do
you have any ideas and he mentioned
generally speaking these are types of
things that you don't really respond to
because most time it's just that you've
hit a wall like you can't actually
exploit it but he had done some previous
research that he had published that was
talking about the same exact type of
thing and he was like you know this
feels this this feels like something
that might actually be exploitable let
me let me take a closer look
and sure enough
you literally just you put the whole you
put the whole request in there just
literally
and you just turned it into two requests
and you have almost like exact like
standard HTTP requests smuggling and he
did uh he did talk about some of the
nuances which is really nice about
um some of the more modern preventions
that are coming into play around this
yeah um where like a lot of times
browsers if it receives two content
lengths it'll stop uh it'll truncate the
data that it receives uh early because
the content length is not short enough
um but there are still like other ways
that you can get around that you can you
know either you can give it a longer
content length you can fiddle with it or
you can get it to maybe
um you can get it to be in the in the
response queue instead so you get like a
full response back
um but uh yeah no this was an awesome
bug from James James has just like he's
whenever I think of request smuggling he
kills it man he kills it he's done so
much unique at original research on
request smuggling that's all like
published and he's given like so many
talks and stuff um yeah it's uh every
time I see another post about I'm like
dang how much further can we go with
request of ugly and it seems like
there's no end yeah and seriously and I
think I think uh I think in one of the
descriptions of the uh write-ups in on
the top 10 web hacking techniques I
think he could yeah here it is as noted
by file descriptor it seems like there's
an infinite amount of anomalies among
proxies that bring you an infinite
amount of requests smuggling techniques
very well said I totally agree
um once again another Banger by by James
um yeah I I really like this and I've
always I've always thought um and well
actually let me let me say this first it
makes me think of another article that I
read um in 2020 by Franz the king
himself Franz
um uh regarding nginx misconfigurations
so I'm going to link that below we don't
have time to go into the details of it
now but
um really awesome read uh you know Franz
is number one on this uh top web hacking
techniques list so we'll you'll
definitely hear more from him but pretty
much anything that's published on
detectify from Franz is like straight
gold so definitely check those out yeah
I feel like Franz is getting to the
level where like anytime you see like a
new project zero blog post you're like
uh oh this is probably bad and same
thing if I see a new Franz like
detectify blog post uh-oh yeah no for
sure man and I was catching up with him
you know uh what event was that at he
was at one of the events that I was at
recently and I was catching up with him
and he like runs a couple companies too
and like does all this like I'm just
like who are you like how do you do this
yeah family yeah it's amazing so yeah
really cool stuff goals there
um
let's see yeah no I don't think I have
any other comments on this one this
one's pretty pretty cool how they just
wrote out the whole HTTP request I think
you did a great job explaining it so I
guess we'll leave it there
um let's see what time are we at we're
at 49 minutes right now
um yeah all right I'll talk real quickly
I'm not going to get to talk about that
bug that I was going to talk about uh
Joel but we'll we'll actually I'll give
you guys I'll I'll do the CSS bug that I
was talking about next time
um and we'll you know we'll spend some
decent amount of time there I did want
to shoot out
a couple tips here at the end
um one and you'll see this when we get
to number one on the list uh but Franz
is
post message tracker extension is a
necessity that is absolutely something
everyone should have installed Go
download that and keep your you know
inspect your Dev tools tab open to see
what kind of post messages are being
sent because there's a lot of scope
there and it's it's pretty much like an
API for the browser that you can access
cross-origin depending on how it's set
up so it's it's really it's definitely
something that should be paid attention
to it's it's pretty awesome I forgot
that this was actually a public tool
because friends gave me a private copy
of it yeah many years ago and uh and I
was using that for a while and then
eventually he finally released it and
but for those who aren't familiar it's
essentially it's a browser plug-in that
will log all of the data that's going
um in post message calls so between like
Windows or between tabs via you know
window.post message
um and it's really really insightful
because that's an awesome Vector for
like xss CSS RF there's like a million
different things that you can do and you
can see all the different data that's
being triggered between the two events
whether or not there's an origin check
all that kind of stuff so
there there's a lot of really really
juicy stuff to be had and uh yeah that
tool is free and available so go get it
yeah I'm gonna go ahead and just add
these right right now to the show
actually I also did a little bit of a
write-up on post message stuff where I
mentioned his uh his tracker extension
in a little bit more detail so I'm going
to link that below as well I actually
think it's really good at the pace we're
going to because we've basically gone
through uh number 10 through 4 through
the five or four yeah and uh I think
what what we might do is we'll leave the
last the top three for the listener so
if you're interested and you've liked
what you've heard so far I mean the top
three are like even better right it's
like so freaking good it's like and
number one like I said number one is a
friends Rosenberg it's an amazing
write-up
um there's just like so many awesome
techniques and takeaways that you can
get from all of these so I would
encourage you to just go back even if
you've listened to us talk about these
go back and read them yourself the
write-ups were were really only like
skimming over them I don't think we can
fold Justice not even close every single
write-up and so definitely takes takes
some time make some notes I feel like I
have
like an endless list of like new things
that I need to be checking for now it's
whatever I'm hacking on targets and
especially around request smuggling uh
it's just like man there's so there's so
much unexplored attack service yeah for
sure man
um all right that's a wrap I don't think
I've got anything else in the tips
section
um we always appreciate you I mean you
could see at the beginning of the
episode how excited we were about those
reviews
um and uh you know ratings on Apple
podcasts and on Spotify and wherever you
listen so definitely do us a solid and
leave us some reviews and uh yeah we'll
we'll talk to you next week on the Pod
oh I actually do have one one quick tip
something that I I told you wow Joel
coming out here with a with a tip I
saved it well it's not even in the dock
Joel I know it's written on a sticky
note on my desk so um
so I I had told you about this after our
episode yesterday but I wanted to to
pass it on to the to the community
um one of our hacking buddies uh had
mentioned that they got an Akamai bin
and we talked a little bit about it yeah
yeah these bugs but if you ever come
across an Akamai bin you've been a
little too aggressive on your scanning
your payloads or whatever we've all been
there I definitely was not banned from
USPS for like three weeks gosh
but um but yeah if you ever come across
an Akamai bin uh one
you can go to akamai's site and you can
check there's like a button that you can
click that will tell you the reputation
for your current IP sort of tell you
whether or not you've been flagged and
whether why you've been flagged and
whether or not you know you can access
Akamai websites but if you want to get
around that immediately you can change
the MAC address on your router so most
routers I think probably
I don't think I've ever seen a router
that doesn't let you do it but generally
speaking you can go in and you can
change the MAC address for your router
itself and it's essentially the same as
changing a MAC address on like your
laptop right your the router no longer
identifies the same client so it gives
you a new IP address same thing with
your ISB your ISP no longer recognizes
your router gives you no IP so you can
just trick DHCP into giving you a new
public IP address by just changing your
router Mac by like one character and
then you can just leave it like that for
a couple weeks set a reminder change it
back and you'll be good to go
on that same page that I mentioned that
Akamai you can look up your IP
reputation there's also like an appeal
button or something and I'd also
recommend just hit that say I'm you know
I'm a security researcher I was
authorized to do the scanning and
you know if you you can't wait just
change your Mac by a little bit and
you'll get a new public IP nice Pro tips
man Pro tips that those bands are so
annoying and and I'm gonna just I'm
gonna keep rolling man I got another tip
that popped into my brain Joel Joel uh
Joel style
um on this note of changing the Mac
um I think this is a pretty classic tip
but for most web people I'm not sure
it's it's super intuitive but I was um I
was doing a physical uh test one time
and I got on a network and I plugged up
an ethernet cable to my laptop and it
wouldn't give me an IP address and I was
like ah what's going on well the device
that I had unplugged I plugged that into
my laptop and I opened up Wireshark and
I grabbed the MAC address for that
um for that specific device and I
spooked my Mac address to that Mac
address and then I plugged back up to
the network and I got an IP so
um it's a it's you know just a little
little little tip here and there and you
know maybe you'll use that in your in
your next physical stuff that you do
yeah you never know when that's going to
come in handy
sweet cool that it that's it for me all
right sweet that's the Pod see you guys
next week awesome take care
I definitely just left it engine
recording
dude I was just sitting here